Based on the incredible true story that captivated the world.
Cave Rescue is a adventure, drama film directed by Tom Waller.
When a youth football team of 12 boys, aged 11-16, and their 25-year-old coach is trapped deep inside a cave in Northern
Thailand, thousands of volunteers and soldiers from around the world unite in a race against time to find them.
Jim, played by Jim Warny.
Coach, played by Ekawat Niratvorapanya.
USAF Major, played by James Edward Holley.
Tun, played by Nopadol Niyomka.
Bua, played by Jampar Saenprom.
Tan, played by Tan Xiaolong.
In June 2018, a junior association football team became trapped in Tham Luang
Nang Non, a cave system in Chiang Rai province, northern Thailand.
Twelve members of the team, aged 11 to 16, and their 25-year-old assistant
coach entered the cave on 23 June after a practice session.
Shortly after they entered, heavy rainfall began and partially flooded the cave
system, blocking their way out and trapping them deep within.
Efforts to locate the group were hampered by rising water levels and strong currents, and
the team were out of contact with the outside world for more than a week.
The cave rescue effort expanded into a massive operation amid intense
worldwide public interest and involved international rescue teams.
On 2 July, after advancing through narrow passages and muddy waters, British divers John Volanthen and Rick
Stanton found the group alive on an elevated rock about 4 kilometres (2.5 mi) from the cave mouth.
Rescue organisers discussed various options for extracting the group, including whether to teach them basic underwater diving skills to enable their early rescue, to
wait until a new entrance to the cave was found or drilled or to wait for the floodwaters to subside by the end of the monsoon season several months later.
After days of pumping water from the cave system and a respite from the rainfall, the rescue teams worked quickly to extract the
group from the cave before the next monsoon rain, which was expected to bring additional downpours on 11 July.
Between 8 and 10 July, all 12 boys and their coach were
rescued from the cave by an international team.
The rescue effort involved as many as 10,000 people, including more than 100 divers, scores of rescue workers,
representatives from about 100 governmental agencies, 900 police officers and 2,000 soldiers.
Ten police helicopters, seven ambulances, more than 700 diving cylinders and the pumping
of more than one billion litres of water from the caves were required.
Saman Kunan, a 37-year-old former Royal Thai Navy SEAL, died of asphyxiation during an attempted rescue on 6 July
while returning to a staging base in the cave after delivering diving cylinders to the trapped group.
The following year, in December 2019, rescue diver and Thai Navy SEAL Beirut
Pakbara died of a blood infection contracted during the operation.
The film explores themes of rescue mission, based on true story, docudrama.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.